Guide to the Association for Asian Studies. Southeast Conference Records, 1964-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Association for Asian Studies. Southeast Conference records 1964-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Association for Asian Studies. Southeast Conference.
4 Linear Feet 9,725 Items
Association for Asian Studies is a scholarly, non-political, non-profit professional association open to all persons interested in East, South, and Southeast Asia.
The Association for Asian Studies (AAS) was founded in 1941. The Southeast Regional Conference of the Association for Asian Studies (SEC/AAS) is a non-political, non-profit scholarly organization dedicated to promoting the study of Asia in the southeastern region of the United States.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Association for Asian Studies Southeast Conference Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1985, 1993, 1997, 2001, and 2004.
Collection Overview
The Association for Asian Studies (AAS), founded in 1941, is a scholarly, non-political, non-profit professional association open to all persons interested in East, South, and Southeast Asia. The Southeast Regional Conference of the Association for Asian Studies (SEC/AAS) is a non-political, non-profit scholarly organization dedicated to promoting the study of Asia in the southeastern region of the United States.
Collection (ca. 3300 items, dated 1964-1988) includes records pertaining to the conference's primary mandate--to promote the study of Asia in the southeastern region of the United States. Materials include correspondence, memoranda, and printed material relating to the organization's activities. Also included are programs, minutes, and letters for annual meetings (1964-1988), as well as a history of the association, membership lists, and documentation for an occasional papers project. (3-15-85?)
Addition 93-178 Series (3500 items, dated 1979-1993) contains copies of the association's ANNALS publication, volumes I-XI; correspondence, secretary and treasurer's papers; as well as papers presented at annual meetings.
Addition 97-007 Series (ca. 900 items, dated 1994-1996) includes 44 folders of materials concerning annual meetings and other activities of the organization.
Addition 01-006 Series (1000 items, dated 1994-2000) includes annual meeting documents, business and annual reports, and student prize competition papers from 1995 to 2000. At the end of the second box are included materials from 1994-1997 that are similar to those in earlier accessions.
Additions 04-136 and 07-042 Series (1025 items, 1.5 lin. ft.; dated 1991-2006) consists of files related to annual meetings, committees, membership, publications, institutional records relating to 45th annual business meeting and volume 27 of the SOUTHEAST REVIEW OF ASIAN STUDIES. Addition 07-042 has been interfiled in 04/136: Box 3.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Association for Asian Studies. Southeast Conference
Association for Asian Studies. Southeast Conference -- History -- Congresses
Arabists -- United States
Asianists -- United States
Asia -- Study and teaching -- Congresses
Asia -- Study and teaching -- Southern States
Contents of Collection
- Association for Asian Studies. Southeast Conference Records, 1964-1985, (11 boxes)
  Series contains papers from meetings and panels held by the AAS.
  - Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Meetings, 1966-1978 (Box 2)
  - Meetings, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Meetings, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
  - Meetings, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Meetings (Box 6)
  - Meetings, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Meetings, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Meetings, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Meetings, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Meetings, 1989 (Box 11)
- Addition 93-178, 1979-1993, (3 boxes)
  Addition (93-178)(3500 items, dated 1979-1993) contains copies of the association's ANNALS publication, volumes I-XI; correspondence, secretary and treasurer's papers; as well as papers presented at annual meetings.
  - Records, 1979-1993 (Box 1-3)
- Addition 97-007, 1994-1996, (1 box)
  Addition (97-007)(ca. 900 items, dated 1994-1996) includes 44 folders of materials concerning annual meetings and other activities of the organization.
  - Records, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
- Addition 2001-006, 1994-2000, (2 boxes)
  Addition (01-006)(1000 items, dated 1994-2000) includes annual meeting documents, business and annual reports, and student prize competition papers from 1995 to 2000. At the end of the second box are included materials from 1994-1997 that are similar to those in earlier accessions.
  - Records, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1994-1999 (Box 2)
- Additions 2004-042 and 07-042, 1991-2006, (2 boxes)
  Addition (04-136)(975 items, 1.4 lin. ft.; dated 1991-2004) consists of files related to annual meetings, committees, membership, and publications.
  Addition (07-042)(50 items, 0.1 lin. ft; dated 2005-2006) consists of institutional records relating to 45th annual business meeting and volume 27 of the SOUTHEAST REVIEW OF ASIAN STUDIES. Addition has been interfiled in 04/136: Box 3.
  - Records, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1994-1999 (Box 2)